<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/life/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Life</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Life</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/life/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Как прошла моя неделя 3.0</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_week.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_week.3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week began with two lectures on basic programming and mathematical logic. I went to bed at 4 am that day, so I attended the lectures formally. I didn&amp;rsquo;t learn anything, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay. I could figure it out that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was productive. I slept through classes, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t stop me from getting a lot done. I&amp;rsquo;ll give those days a kudos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday&#34;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s day. Doing an individual project today since Saturday is my brother&amp;rsquo;s birthday. Had analytic geometry colloquium today and it went great. I got a 10 out of 10. I have a lot of plans for today, so it promises to be a productive day as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday will probably be like Thursday. Can&amp;rsquo;t say anything about the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday is the day we sit at the university until 7:20 p.m. in English. It&amp;rsquo;s become a no-brainer because it&amp;rsquo;s getting late dark outside and the weather is beautiful. And no, I&amp;rsquo;m not going away to Vladimir, because Saturday is history, I&amp;rsquo;ll be preparing a report in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saturday&#34;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Birthday bro!!! The man is turning 19 years old. I hope you will join me in congratulating him. Plan for the day: go to the story, tell the first report, run to the train, and get to Vladimir as soon as possible for his birthday. The evening will be beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Как прошла моя неделя 4.0</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_week.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_week.4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was extremely busy because the May holidays came. I spent Monday in St. Petersburg. There are no distance couples today, so I just relaxed and walked around St. Petersburg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was the 9th of May. Happy Holidays to all! Also spent it in St. Petersburg. I slept through all the parades, but had a good walk, went to Lakhta center and visited an amusement park near it. It had this amazing roller coaster. I was happy with it, but it cost a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday&#34;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back to Moscow, but I slept through my classes. But I had a good time in the co-working room and did a lot of useful things. Didn&amp;rsquo;t waste the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday was just like Thursday. Everything is business as usual. Couples in the morning, couples in the afternoon, and co-working in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of English on Friday, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to discourage it. On the contrary, in fact. I like the language, although I don&amp;rsquo;t know it perfectly. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to strive for. Going home in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saturday&#34;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday was also an unremarkable Saturday. I did my homework all day and am still doing it at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Как прошла моя неделя 2.0</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_week.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_week.2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week started the way a normal university week starts. I barely woke up because yesterday (today) I sat up until 4 am doing my homework and watching youtube at the same time. The distance lectures started, which I listened to VERY carefully. After that I had to go to Moscow, because tomorrow are full-time classes, and I am at home, in Vladimir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was an unremarkable day. There were only two classes: calculus and computer algebra. The interesting thing is that we had a new math analysis instructor. The BRS changed again, which is good (for me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday&#34;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday we have only math. we got the results of the test in analytical geometry. To make a long story short, I&amp;rsquo;m off to rewrite. The next pair was mat logic. Cr again. This time I was better prepared and solved everything, hopefully correctly. I also decided to finally get some exercise and ran in the park for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this day I had to do a big homework on programming technologies. I almost did it, but I still had to finish it and hand it in next week. Then I had two lectures, I tried to stay awake and I almost made it (on angem for sure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English Day is the name of Friday. It is because we have 3 classes in this subject today. Often near the end, I&amp;rsquo;ll do anything to get them over with. It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that this time the class went a lot easier than usual. Probably because it got darker later in the day. At the end of the day I drove home to Vladimir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concludes the description of my week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Как прошла моя неделя 5.0</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_week.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_week.5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Moscow on Monday. Nothing remarkable happened, I studied all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was supposed to be a math analysis quiz, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t, so we got lucky. We got our results in Mathematical Logic, seems ok but could have been better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday&#34;&gt;Wednesday.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday had only one event, a quiz on analytic geometry. Wrote it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday was also standard. I was able to understand programming techniques, which is good. Went to a lecture on calculus and spent the rest of the day in the co-working room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English day again. Only went to it. Three classes went well and at the end of the last one I handed in my essay okay. After that I went to Vladimir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concludes the description of my week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Как прошла моя неделя.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my_week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was only one class on Monday, where I gave my report. I never got a grade on it.The day continued with a long preparation for the upcoming math analysis quiz. I would have to solve some integrals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day of the test came and I felt ready enough to write a satisfying score. In the end I was only able to write a list of table integrals. In the main part I started with the hardest and ended up not having enough time to solve the easy assignments, because there were 5 minutes left (spoiler: I solved the hard assignment wrong). Dear diary&amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t put into words the pain I felt today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday&#34;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results came back on the test paper, I got a 0). For the next two weeks getting ready to rewrite. Otherwise, a normal day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only interesting thing was that I was able to pass my programming technology assignment with a maximum score, but neither I nor the instructor understood how one piece of my code worked. There are a few hypotheses, next week it will become clearer. I hope I don&amp;rsquo;t lose points because of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day is notable because I will finally go home to Vladimir, where I have not been for three weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there to celebrate my mother&amp;rsquo;s birthday. The end of the week will be beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concludes the description of my week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
